[
    {
        "question": "(1) \u201cAnd it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my Spirit on all flesh; your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, your old men shall dream dreams, and your young men shall see visions. Footnotes (1) 2:28 Ch 3:1 in Hebrew (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:28",
        "rank": "90"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fire devours before them, and behind them a flame burns. The land is like the garden of Eden before them, but behind them a desolate wilderness, and nothing escapes them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:3",
        "rank": "498"
    },
    {
        "question": "And it shall come to pass that everyone who calls on the name of the LORD shall be saved. For in Mount Zion and in Jerusalem there shall be those who escape, as the LORD has said, and among the survivors shall be those whom the LORD calls. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:32",
        "rank": "1,326"
    },
    {
        "question": "Blow a trumpet in Zion; sound an alarm on my holy mountain! Let all the inhabitants of the land tremble, for the day of the LORD is coming; it is near, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:1",
        "rank": "1,555"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYet even now,\u201d declares the LORD, \u201creturn to me with all your heart, with fasting, with weeping, and with mourning; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:12",
        "rank": "1,579"
    },
    {
        "question": "Their appearance is like the appearance of horses, and like war horses they run. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:4",
        "rank": "1,901"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cWhat are you to me, O Tyre and Sidon, and all the regions of Philistia? Are you paying me back for something? If you are paying me back, I will return your payment on your own head swiftly and speedily. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:4",
        "rank": "2,086"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFor behold, in those days and at that time, when I restore the fortunes of Judah and Jerusalem, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:1",
        "rank": "2,356"
    },
    {
        "question": "What the cutting locust left, the swarming locust has eaten. What the swarming locust left, the hopping locust has eaten, and what the hopping locust left, the destroying locust has eaten. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:4",
        "rank": "2,412"
    },
    {
        "question": "and rend your hearts and not your garments.\u201d Return to the LORD your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love; and he relents over disaster. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:13",
        "rank": "2,523"
    },
    {
        "question": "Awake, you drunkards, and weep, and wail, all you drinkers of wine, because of the sweet wine, for it is cut off from your mouth. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:5",
        "rank": "3,057"
    },
    {
        "question": "As with the rumbling of chariots, they leap on the tops of the mountains, like the crackling of a flame of fire devouring the stubble, like a powerful army drawn up for battle. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:5",
        "rank": "3,126"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a nation has come up against my land, powerful and beyond number; its teeth are lions\u2019 teeth, and it has the fangs of a lioness. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:6",
        "rank": "3,482"
    },
    {
        "question": "It has laid waste my vine and splintered my fig tree; it has stripped off their bark and thrown it down; their branches are made white. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:7",
        "rank": "3,525"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lament like a virgin(1) wearing sackcloth for the bridegroom of her youth. Footnotes (1) 1:8 Or *young woman* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:8",
        "rank": "3,540"
    },
    {
        "question": "Be ashamed,(1) O tillers of the soil; wail, O vinedressers, for the wheat and the barley, because the harvest of the field has perished. Footnotes (1) 1:11 The Hebrew words for *dry up* and *be ashamed* in verses 10\u201312, 17 sound alike (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:11",
        "rank": "3,595"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before them peoples are in anguish; all faces grow pale. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:6",
        "rank": "3,606"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fields are destroyed, the ground mourns, because the grain is destroyed, the wine dries up, the oil languishes. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:10",
        "rank": "3,639"
    },
    {
        "question": "For you have taken my silver and my gold, and have carried my rich treasures into your temples.(1) Footnotes (1) 3:5 Or *palaces* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:5",
        "rank": "3,675"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consecrate a fast; call a solemn assembly. Gather the elders and all the inhabitants of the land to the house of the LORD your God, and cry out to the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:14",
        "rank": "3,823"
    },
    {
        "question": "The grain offering and the drink offering are cut off from the house of the LORD. The priests mourn, the ministers of the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:9",
        "rank": "3,838"
    },
    {
        "question": "The vine dries up; the fig tree languishes. Pomegranate, palm, and apple, all the trees of the field are dried up, and gladness dries up from the children of man. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:12",
        "rank": "3,851"
    },
    {
        "question": "Put on sackcloth and lament, O priests; wail, O ministers of the altar. Go in, pass the night in sackcloth, O ministers of my God! Because grain offering and drink offering are withheld from the house of your God. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:13",
        "rank": "3,929"
    },
    {
        "question": "They do not jostle one another; each marches in his path; they burst through the weapons and are not halted. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:8",
        "rank": "4,003"
    },
    {
        "question": "The seed shrivels under the clods;(1) the storehouses are desolate; the granaries are torn down because the grain has dried up. Footnotes (1) 1:17 The meaning of the Hebrew line is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:17",
        "rank": "4,118"
    },
    {
        "question": "Like warriors they charge; like soldiers they scale the wall. They march each on his way; they do not swerve from their paths. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:7",
        "rank": "4,155"
    },
    {
        "question": "Even the beasts of the field pant for you because the water brooks are dried up, and fire has devoured the pastures of the wilderness. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:20",
        "rank": "4,241"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have sold the people of Judah and Jerusalem to the Greeks in order to remove them far from their own border. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:6",
        "rank": "4,251"
    },
    {
        "question": "How the beasts groan! The herds of cattle are perplexed because there is no pasture for them; even the flocks of sheep suffer.(1) Footnotes (1) 1:18 Or *are made desolate* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:18",
        "rank": "4,264"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is not the food cut off before our eyes, joy and gladness from the house of our God? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:16",
        "rank": "4,318"
    },
    {
        "question": "To you, O LORD, I call. For fire has devoured the pastures of the wilderness, and flame has burned all the trees of the field. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:19",
        "rank": "4,492"
    },
    {
        "question": "They leap upon the city, they run upon the walls, they climb up into the houses, they enter through the windows like a thief. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:9",
        "rank": "4,871"
    },
    {
        "question": "Between the vestibule and the altar let the priests, the ministers of the LORD, weep and say, \u201cSpare your people, O LORD, and make not your heritage a reproach, a byword among the nations.(1) Why should they say among the peoples, \u2018Where is their God?\u2019\u201d Footnotes (1) 2:17 Or *reproach, that the nations should rule over them* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:17",
        "rank": "4,920"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, I will stir them up from the place to which you have sold them, and I will return your payment on your own head. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:7",
        "rank": "5,127"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the LORD became jealous for his land and had pity on his people. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:18",
        "rank": "5,200"
    },
    {
        "question": "gather the people. Consecrate the congregation; assemble the elders; gather the children, even nursing infants. Let the bridegroom leave his room, and the bride her chamber. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:16",
        "rank": "5,250"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will sell your sons and daughters to the people of Judah, and they will sell them to the Sabeans, a nation far away.\" The LORD has spoken.\"",
        "answer": "Joel 3:8",
        "rank": "5,411"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Then you will know that I, the LORD your God, dwell in Zion, my holy hill. Jerusalem will be holy; never again will foreigners invade her.\"",
        "answer": "Joel 3:17",
        "rank": "5,542"
    },
    {
        "question": "Beat your plowshares into swords and your pruning hooks into spears. Let the weakling say, \"I am strong!\"",
        "answer": "Joel 3:10",
        "rank": "5,720"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who knows? He may turn and relent and leave behind a blessing \u2013  grain offerings and drink offerings for the LORD your God.",
        "answer": "Joel 2:14",
        "rank": "5,740"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD answered and said to his people, \u201cBehold, I am sending to you grain, wine, and oil, and you will be satisfied; and I will no more make you a reproach among the nations. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:19",
        "rank": "6,018"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sun and the moon are darkened, and the stars withdraw their shining. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:15",
        "rank": "6,040"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI will remove the northerner far from you, and drive him into a parched and desolate land, his vanguard(1) into the eastern sea, and his rear guard(2) into the western sea; the stench and foul smell of him will rise, for he has done great things. Footnotes (1) 2:20 Hebrew *face* (2) 2:20 Hebrew *his end* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:20",
        "rank": "6,251"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYou shall eat in plenty and be satisfied, and praise the name of the LORD your God, who has dealt wondrously with you. And my people shall never again be put to shame. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:26",
        "rank": "6,446"
    },
    {
        "question": "Let the nations stir themselves up and come up to the Valley of Jehoshaphat; for there I will sit to judge all the surrounding nations. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:12",
        "rank": "6,479"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hasten and come, all you surrounding nations, and gather yourselves there. Bring down your warriors, O LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:11",
        "rank": "6,480"
    },
    {
        "question": "Put in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe. Go in, tread, for the winepress is full. The vats overflow, for their evil is great. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:13",
        "rank": "6,531"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThe threshing floors shall be full of grain; the vats shall overflow with wine and oil. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:24",
        "rank": "6,532"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fear not, you beasts of the field, for the pastures of the wilderness are green; the tree bears its fruit; the fig tree and vine give their full yield. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:22",
        "rank": "7,450"
    },
    {
        "question": "You shall know that I am in the midst of Israel, and that I am the LORD your God and there is none else. And my people shall never again be put to shame. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:27",
        "rank": "7,595"
    },
    {
        "question": "and have cast lots for my people, and have traded a boy for a prostitute, and have sold a girl for wine and have drunk it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:3",
        "rank": "7,671"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cEgypt shall become a desolation and Edom a desolate wilderness, for the violence done to the people of Judah, because they have shed innocent blood in their land. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:19",
        "rank": "8,371"
    },
    {
        "question": "But Judah shall be inhabited forever, and Jerusalem to all generations. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:20",
        "rank": "9,345"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will avenge their blood, blood I have not avenged,(1) for the LORD dwells in Zion.\u201d Footnotes (1) 3:21 Or *I will acquit their bloodguilt that I have not acquitted* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:21",
        "rank": "9,506"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBe glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the LORD your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:23",
        "rank": "9,721"
    },
    {
        "question": "Even on the male and female servants in those days I will pour out my Spirit. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:29",
        "rank": "10,441"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alas for the day! For the day of the LORD is near, and as destruction from the Almighty(1) it comes. Footnotes (1) 1:15 *Destruction* sounds like the Hebrew for *Almighty* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:15",
        "rank": "10,947"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will gather all the nations and bring them down to the Valley of Jehoshaphat. And I will enter into judgment with them there, on behalf of my people and my heritage Israel, because they have scattered them among the nations and have divided up my land, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:2",
        "rank": "11,010"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAnd in that day the mountains shall drip sweet wine, and the hills shall flow with milk, and all the streambeds of Judah shall flow with water; and a fountain shall come forth from the house of the LORD and water the Valley of Shittim. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 3:18",
        "rank": "11,432"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sun shall be turned to darkness, and the moon to blood, before the great and awesome day of the LORD comes. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:31",
        "rank": "11,582"
    },
    {
        "question": "The earth quakes before them; the heavens tremble. The sun and the moon are darkened, and the stars withdraw their shining. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:10",
        "rank": "12,035"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word of the LORD that came to Joel, the son of Pethuel: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 1:1",
        "rank": "12,036"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will restore(1) to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten, the hopper, the destroyer, and the cutter, my great army, which I sent among you. Footnotes (1) 2:25 Or *pay back* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:25",
        "rank": "12,293"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAnd I will show wonders in the heavens and on the earth, blood and fire and columns of smoke. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Joel 2:30",
        "rank": "12,852"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hear this, you elders; listen, all who live in the land. Has anything like this ever happened in your days or in the days of your ancestors?",
        "answer": "Joel 1:2",
        "rank": "13,682"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD will roar from Zion and thunder from Jerusalem; the earth and the heavens will tremble. But the LORD will be a refuge for his people, a stronghold for the people of Israel.",
        "answer": "Joel 3:16",
        "rank": "14,608"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD thunders at the head of his army; his forces are beyond number, and mighty is the army that obeys his command. The day of the LORD is great; it is dreadful. Who can endure it?",
        "answer": "Joel 2:11",
        "rank": "14,688"
    },
    {
        "question": "Proclaim this among the nations: Prepare for war! Rouse the warriors! Let all the fighting men draw near and attack.",
        "answer": "Joel 3:9",
        "rank": "14,774"
    },
    {
        "question": "Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision! For the day of the LORD is near in the valley of decision.",
        "answer": "Joel 3:14",
        "rank": "14,965"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do not be afraid, land of Judah; be glad and rejoice. Surely the LORD has done great things!",
        "answer": "Joel 2:21",
        "rank": "16,130"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tell it to your children, and let your children tell it to their children, and their children to the next generation.",
        "answer": "Joel 1:3",
        "rank": "16,146"
    },
    {
        "question": "Blow the trumpet in Zion, declare a holy fast, call a sacred assembly.",
        "answer": "Joel 2:15",
        "rank": "16,211"
    },
    {
        "question": "A day of darkness and gloom, a day of clouds and blackness. Like dawn spreading across the mountains a large and mighty army comes, such as never was of old nor ever will be in ages to come.",
        "answer": "Joel 2:2",
        "rank": "17,333"
    }
]